Keenan Brant

Software Developer

Barnsley (open to relocation)

07867-861-565 | keenan.brant@yahoo.co.uk
GitHub | Portfolio | LinkedIn

Profile

A junior software developer with full stack programming skills and prior technical knowledge of computer hardware and software looking for a role where I can utilise my skills and expand upon them with new knowledge learned on the job. I initially spent 2 years at Sheffield Hallam University studying Cyber Security and Computer Networks prior to Covid resulting in a career/education gap, in May 2023 I joined the Northcoders Software Development Bootcamp where I developed fundamental coding skills and software practices with a focus on fullstack web development using JS frameworks and libraries and relation database management software.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript and TypeScript using Node.JS w/ express.JS, web browsers and Electron as environments. C# and ASP.NET core in .NET7

Testing: Test Driven Development (TDD), Jest, Swagger, Postman/Insomnia

Back-end: SQL and PostgreSQL, seeding, Entity Framework core, migrations, RESTful API

Front-end: HTML CSS, Tailwind CSS, React and React Native, UI/UX, responsive design,

Lighthouse & AXE accessibility tools and WCAG compliance

Hosting: Netlify, GitHub Pages

Environments: Linux, WSL

Soft skills: Version control with Git, pair programming, technical communications, documentation, Software Development Lifecycle (SDL), Agile Scrum and Kanban methodologies, Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD), GitHub Actions

Well versed in IT technical skills including maintaining and installing computer hardware directly, the installation and maintenance of software and proficiency with software packages such as troubleshooting support software and the adobe CC suite.

Professional Experience

Trainee Software Developer, Northcoders Software Dev Bootcamp

May 2023 to Aug 2023

- Award winning 13-week software development bootcamp teaching Full-Stack and fundamental
 coding skills with a focus on PERN stack Web development and methodologies via project-based
 learning with portfolio pieces displayed on GitHub.
- Back-end skills demonstrated by building and hosting a RESTful news API made with NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL and Jest. This API was built and documented with CRUD operational routes and custom error handling using express middleware hosted with OnRender with an on-demandwindup service. Live Project | GitHub Repo
- Front-end skills demonstrated by a responsive mobile-first news web-app built using HTML, CSS, React, JavaScript and MUI component libraries, this is a dynamic web-app linking to a RESTful API that can be interacted with and changed through user actions such as ratings and comments. Live Project | GitHub Repo
- Team development skills demonstrated by an independent team project using kanban and scrum methods in the development process involving outreach into new technologies using the available documentation to develop a cross platform mobile app using React Native with Expo where I was

primarily responsible for testing and developing geolocation and mapping functionality using Google Maps with Expo Location and displaying chosen locations dynamically and programmatically with data received from the backend team as well as having the task of designing native forms to enable other frontend team members to implement logic and auth functionality without issue. FE Repo | BE Repo

Library Front Desk, Wath Public Library (Work Placement)

Dec 2017 to Dec 2017

- Working with the library database system to manage outbound and incoming inventory and reservations
- Providing customer service and IT technical support
- Management of incoming calls and payment to front desk or escalating to library manager

Product line worker, Vortex Clothing Co Ltd (Work Placement)

Dec 2015 to Dec 2015

- Operation of various graphics application machinery
- End of line quality assurance to meet the required standards
- · Preparation of graphics transferred from digital to physical format for machinery
- Stocking and maintenance of bespoke graphics equipment for regular customers and large orders
- Managing logistics and paperwork of orders due for distribution

Education & Qualifications

•	Sheffield Hallam University - Cyber Security and Computer Networks	2018 – 2020
•	Dearne Valley College, Manvers - BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma ICT (DMM)	2018
•	Netherwood ALC, Wombwell - 6 GCSE's and 1 BTEC including English, Maths and	2015
	Science at grades C	

Hobbies / Interests

- Maintenance of personal PC system including keeping in good functioning order or upgrading as required.
- Experimenting with new technologies and developing trends to exercise and develop problem solving skills in a dynamic and challenging environment.
- Personal physical fitness involving technical anatomical knowledge, record keeping and personal growth.